这是普通高等学校招生
全国统一考试英语科听力部分。
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷。
啊，听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
现在是。
听力试音时间。
Hello, International Friends Club.
Can I help you?
Oh, hello. I read about your club in the paper today and I thought I'd phone to find
out a bit more.
Yes, certainly. Well, we're sort of a social club for people from different
countries. It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
What kinds of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages, you know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian,
Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
Okay. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form
and some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。
听力考试正式开始。
请看听力部分第一节。
第一节。
听下面五段录音，每段录音后有一个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段录音后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有。
关小题和阅读下一小题，
每段录音播放两遍。
现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容
听下面的录音，回答第一小题。
Excuse me, is there a flower shop nearby?
Yes. Do you see the bakery over there?
Next to it, you'll see a red umbrella.
That's where the flower shop is.
听下面的录音，回答第二小题。
听下面的录音，回答第三小题。
It's much bigger.
I know, but it's always packed with people.
Which supermarket do you usually go to?
I always shop at Brown's.
A new supermarket has opened in this area.
It's much bigger.
I know, but it's always packed with people.
听下面的录音，回答第四小题。
Listen to the following recordings and answer the fifth question.
听下面的录音，回答第五小题。
I'd like to summarize what it is we're looking for.
Good. Basically, we want the printing cost to come down by 15%.
Well, it's really hard for us to offer such a price cut.
I'd like to summarize what it is we're looking for.
Good. we want the printing cost to come down
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下。
下面五段录音，每段录音后有几个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段录音前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，每小题都有五秒钟的作答时间。
每段录音播放两遍。
听下面的录音，回答第六和第七小题。
现在你有十秒。
中的时间阅读这两个小题。
Yeah, many people hope to be healthier in the new year.
You always see a lot of people start joining gyms.
I heard some kind of statistic that gyms are always 50 more crowded in the month of
January, and then usually by February, it's back to normal.
That's so true.
It's always difficult to keep up the workout routine.
Happy New Year, Mike.
Happy New Year.
Have you made any resolutions?
I'd like to eat less and exercise more this year.
Three hamburgers a day is probably not a good idea.
Yeah, many people hope to be healthier in the new year.
You always see a lot of people start joining gyms.
I heard some kind of statistic that gyms are always 50 more crowded in the month of
January, and then usually by February, it's back to normal.
That's so true.
It's always difficult to keep up the workout routine.
听下面的录音，回答第八至第十小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Would you like to come?
Thanks, but I'll be busy tomorrow.
No problem. Maybe another time.
Do you have plans?
Yes. I'll meet Katie at the Olympia Exhibition Center.
Remember her? We went to the same art school.
Some of her designs are going to be exhibited there.
She's hoping one of the big clothes companies might buy them.
Setting her sights high, isn't she?
Yeah, she is aiming high, but she has what it takes to get there.
Fenny, if you're up in London tomorrow, I've got two tickets for the American Ballet
Theater. Would you like to come?
Thanks, but I'll be busy tomorrow.
No problem. Maybe another time.
Do you have plans?
Yes. I'll meet Katie at the Olympia Exhibition Center.
Remember her? We went to the same art school.
Some of her designs are going to be exhibited there.
She's hoping one of the big clothes companies might buy them.
Setting her sights high, isn't she?
Yeah, she is aiming high, but she has what it takes to get there.
听下面的录音，回答第十一至第十三小题。
现在你有十五秒钟。
的时间阅读这三个小题
People are increasingly concerned about online security, and many experts are now
offering advice on how to use smartphones safely.
What advice? Let me ask you first.
How long have you kept your phone on so far?
For over a year now.
It's not that I'm addicted to it or have important calls.
But I need the alarm to wake me up every morning.
Yeah, but that's where the risk is.
According to experts, we should switch our phones off and on once a day as a
security measure. It helps close the applications running in the background and stop
data collection processes we're not aware of.
Sounds reasonable.
Do we switch the phone off and switch it back on immediately?
Well, better wait for a few minutes.
When do you usually do that?
I do it every night before going to bed.
People are increasingly concerned about online security, and many experts are now
offering advice on how to use smartphones safely.
What advice? Let me ask you first.
How long have you kept your phone on so far?
For over a year now.
It's not that I'm addicted to it or have important calls.
But I need the alarm to wake me up every morning.
Yeah, but that's where the risk is.
According to experts, we should switch our phones off and on once a day as a
security measure. It helps close the applications running in the background and stop
data collection processes we're not aware of.
Sounds reasonable.
Do we switch the phone off and switch it back on immediately?
Well, better wait for a few minutes.
When do you usually do that?
I do it every night before going
听下面的录音。
嗯，回答第十四至第十六小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Welcome to History of the English Language.
Since the class is quite small, I plan to run this course as a discussion.
I hope everyone will be fully engaged and volunteer to share your knowledge and
opinions. I won't take attendance, but since part of your grade depends on
participation, I encourage you to come to class.
Professor Moore? Yes?
Could you tell us more about the assessment of the course?
In addition to your participation in class, which accounts for 10%, there will be a
midterm test, 20%, a final exam, 30%, and a research paper, 40%.
Any questions? Do we have any reading assignments?
Yes, I believe you've all got your textbook.
You have to finish reading assigned chapters before each class.
Apart from that, there's a list of books that you're required to read.
Now let's have a close look at it.
Welcome to History of the English Language.
Since the class is quite small, I plan to run this course as a discussion.
I hope everyone will be fully engaged and volunteer to share your knowledge and
opinions. I won't take attendance, but since part of your grade depends on
participation, I encourage you to come to class.
Professor Moore? Yes?
Could you tell us more about the assessment of the course?
Certainly. In addition to your participation in class, which accounts for 10%, there
will be a midterm test, 20%, a final exam, 30%, and a research paper, 40%.
Any questions? Do we have any reading assignments?
Yes, I believe you've all got your textbook.
You have to finish reading assigned chapters before each class.
Apart from that, there's a list of books that you're required to read.
Now let's have a close look at it.
听下面的录音，回答第十七至第二十小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间。
阅读这四个小题。
Hello, everybody. Thanks for your consistent support for our weekly meeting, New
Books Sharing. Today, we've invited Dr.
Casper Melville, lecturer from the University of London.
Dr. Melville started out as a music journalist for a black music magazine called
Blues and Soul.
In 1992, he moved to San Francisco and founded a jazz magazine named On the One with
some friends. They did a really good job, though there was not a lot of money in it.
In 1997, he moved back to London and started teaching and made the decision to find
another way to write about music.
He grew up in London.
He feels that the music in London clubs has formed him, but unfortunately it has
been seriously undervalued by the academic world.
In black music studies, jazz has received great attention, but dance music has been
largely ignored. His book, It's a London Thing, is meant to change that situation.
So let's welcome Dr.
Melville to share with us his ideas in the book.
Hello, everybody. Thanks for your consistent support for our weekly meeting, New
Books Sharing. Today, we've invited Dr.
Casper Melville, lecturer from the University of London.
Dr. Melville started out as a music journalist for a black music magazine called
Blues and Soul.
In 1992, he moved to San Francisco and founded a jazz magazine named On the One with
some friends. They did a really good job, though there was not a lot of money in it.
In 1997, he moved back to London and started teaching and made the decision to find
another way to write about music.
He grew up in London.
He feels that the music in London clubs has formed him, but unfortunately it has
been seriously undervalued by the academic world.
In black music studies, jazz has received great attention, but dance music has been
largely ignored. His book, It's a London Thing, is meant to change that situation.
So let's welcome Dr.
Melville to share with us his ideas in the book.
you.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷。
这样的答案转涂到答题卡上。
听力部分到此结束。